<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Paul Robert Lloyd</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/feeds/combined/"/>
    <id>tag:v2.paulrobertlloyd.com,2013-06-11:/1</id>
    <updated>2015-07-19T21:37:15Z</updated>
    
    <generator uri="http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/">Movable Type Pro 5.2.6</generator>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Lanyards. What Are They Good For?</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/2015/07/lanyards/"/>
        <id>tag:paulrobertlloyd.com,2015://2.443</id>
        <published>2015-07-06T20:46:36Z</published>
        <updated>2015-07-19T21:37:15Z</updated>
        <summary>Lanyards  &#8211;  the piece of fabric that allows you to hang a conference badge from your neck  &#8211;  have a lifespan of just a few hours. How can we change that?</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Robert Lloyd</name>
            <uri>http://paulrobertlloyd.com/</uri>
        </author>
        <category term="conferences" label="Conferences" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="sustainability" label="Sustainability" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/>
        <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/">
            <![CDATA[<img src="/_assets/2015/07/lanyards.jpg" alt="Lanyards. What Are They Good For?"/>]]>
            
            <![CDATA[<p>Like the British cycling team, I&#8217;m a fan of <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/olympics/19174302">marginal gains</a>: small changes that combine to create a greater impact.</p>

<p>One example can be found on the top of every drinks can. For a long time these used ring pulls with a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beverage_can#Pull-tab">pull-tab</a> design, where opening the tab separated it from the can. This resulted in litter and could cause injury if a tab accidentally fell into the can and was later swallowed. These were later replaced by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beverage_can#Stay-on-tab">stay-on-tab</a>, a design in which the tab remains attached and is used as a lever to depress the scored section, and such incidents disappeared.</p>

<p>Likewise, I often wonder what changes could be enacted to negate the need for staples and windowed envelopes; supplanting these would certainly make recycling junk mail easier<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup>, at least.</p>

<h2>A Greener Conference Badge, Part Two</h2>

<p>A few years ago I advocated the use of <a href="http://paulrobertlloyd.com/2010/08/dconstruct_conference_badge/">conference badges that didn&#8217;t need plastic wallets</a>. While some conferences continue using them, many now use the &#8216;<a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20111113011844/http://www.graphpaper.com/2010/06-11_a-book-on-a-hook">book on a hook</a>&#8217; concept to great effect.</p>

<p>Yet this is only half the story. What about the lanyard, the piece of fabric that allows a badge to hang from your neck? For most conferences, these have a lifespan of only a few hours. I tend to keep conference badges as keep sakes, but would happily throw away the lanyards if I didn&#8217;t feel so guilty about doing so.</p>

<p>This got me thinking: how can we decrease the use of lanyards or increase their lifespan? Here are a few options that I&#8217;ve thought of so far:</p>

<h3>Recycle</h3>

<p>Conference organisers wishing to purchase new lanyards can pick ones made from recycled  &#8211;  and recyclable  &#8211;  materials. A number of companies now offer lanyards made of recycled PET drink bottles for example.</p>

<p>Attendees may want to donate used lanyards to a good cause. Right now, <a href="http://www.lanyardlooter.co.uk">James Macaulay is collecting lanyards</a> and donating 50p to the Alzheimer&#8217;s Society for each one he receives. Others may be attempting similar feats; the Guinness <a href="http://www.guinnessworldrecords.com/world-records/largest-collection-of-lanyards/">World Record for the largest collection of lanyards</a> stands at 3,260 and is held by Christian Gferer. You might even find new uses for old lanyards, although useful examples escape me. Beyond that, it seems hanging them up or hiding them away in a box somewhere is the only means of avoiding their disposal.</p>

<h3>Reuse</h3>

<p>Perhaps we should focus on encouraging their reuse. Conference organisers could advertise a &#8216;bring your own lanyard&#8217; policy for example. While that might work to a degree, not every attendee will have a lanyard, or (more likely) remember to bring one. What if, like plastic shopping bags, you had to pay for a new lanyard? An unpopular option, surely.</p>

<p>Organisers of multiple events could collect lanyards at the end of each event they hold. Collection boxes next to the exits manned by volunteers would surely encourage their return  &#8211;  plain, unbranded lanyards would help also.</p>

<p>This is the one aspect of the recent <a href="https://edgeconf.com/2015-london">Edge conference</a> I liked. Warning: I am about to praise Facebook, who hosted the event. They provided organisers with a set of lanyards (colour coded to indicate building access) with plastic wallets into which custom name badges were inserted. At the end of the event, security guards collected the lanyards from attendees as they exited the building. Slightly draconian maybe, but excusable given the underlying purpose.</p>

<p>What&#8217;s not so clear is how organisers of one-off conferences could run such a scheme, unless there were companies (or other conferences) willing to loan out their lanyards.</p>

<h3>Reduce</h3>

<p>If I&#8217;m to take this post to its natural conclusion I should ask: do we need lanyards at all? There are alternative ways of attaching badges, although they do have their downsides: safety pins can damage clothing while stickers are only really useful for one-day events.</p>

<p>But wait, do we need name badges either? Although a small, grassroots event, <a href="http://responsivedayout.com/">Responsive Day Out</a> worked perfectly well by having ticketed attendees wear only a small sticker with the Clearleft logo on it.</p>

<hr />

<p>These are just a few ideas. Having researched this post, I&#8217;ll probably donate my old lanyards to James, but that won&#8217;t stop the burden of responsibility I&#8217;ll feel the next time I&#8217;m handed a badge attached to a lanyard.</p>

<p>Have you been to any conferences that were lanyard free? Do any conferences operate a policy of attendees bringing their own lanyards? Or are there any other ideas I might have missed? Please let me know in the comments.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
    <ol>
        <li id="fn:1">
            <p>Short of ridding ourselves of junk mail of course, which could be the subject of an entirely separate post. <a href="#fnref:1">&#8617;</a></p>
        </li>
    </ol>
</div>

<p><small>(Photograph modified from an original by <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/collylogic/8314870885/">Simon Collison</a>)</small></p>
]]>
            
            
        </content>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>Link: Better CSS with Sass by Cole Henley</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.fivesimplesteps.com/products/better-css-with-sass"/>
        <id>tag:paulrobertlloyd.com,2015://3.442</id>
        <published>2015-07-06T13:59:31Z</published>
        <updated>2017-01-02T19:31:19Z</updated>
        <summary>For those looking for a quick and succinct introduction to Sass, the popular CSS pre-processor, my friend Cole Henley has written a pocket guide: Sass is a tool that takes a lot of the legwork out of writing good CSS&#8230;.</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Robert Lloyd</name>
            <uri>http://paulrobertlloyd.com/</uri>
        </author>
        <category term="books" label="Books" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="sass" label="Sass" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="webdevelopment" label="Web Development" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/>
        <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/">
            
            
            <![CDATA[<p>For those looking for a quick and succinct introduction to Sass, the popular CSS pre-processor, my friend <a href="http://cole007.net">Cole Henley</a> has written a pocket guide:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Sass is a tool that takes a lot of the legwork out of writing good CSS. This pocket guide will provide an overview of how Sass can dramatically improve your workflow and make your CSS more flexible, robust and reusable.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This guide only takes 30 to 45 minutes to read, but on turning the last page you&#8217;ll be up to speed on all the features of Sass, know why you may want to use them and be thinking about building upon these features to take your Sass usage to the next level  &#8211;  careful now! The book is <a href="http://www.fivesimplesteps.com/products/better-css-with-sass">available now from Five Simple Steps</a> for just £3.</p>
]]>
            
            <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/2015/07/better_css_with_sass/" title="Permalink">#</a></p>]]>
        </content>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>Rotterdam Reflections</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/2015/06/rotterdam/"/>
        <id>tag:paulrobertlloyd.com,2015://2.441</id>
        <published>2015-06-25T22:55:52Z</published>
        <updated>2015-06-25T22:01:59Z</updated>
        <summary>Some thoughts after spending a few days in the Netherlands second city.</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Robert Lloyd</name>
            <uri>http://paulrobertlloyd.com/</uri>
        </author>
        <category term="europe" label="Europe" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="thenetherlands" label="The Netherlands" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="travel" label="Travel" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/>
        <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/">
            <![CDATA[<img src="/_assets/2015/06/rotterdam.jpg" alt="Rotterdam Reflections"/>]]>
            
            <![CDATA[<p>After <a href="https://vimeo.com/130840833">speaking at CSS Day in Amsterdam</a>, I decided to head back to Brighton via a few cities in Europe&#8217;s Low Countries.</p>

<p>In drawing a line south between Amsterdam Centraal station and the Eurostar platforms in Brussels, I decided on a short trip that would include a few days in Rotterdam, before heading to the medieval city of Bruges in Belgium, thus providing a deliberate contrast of architectural styles.</p>

<h2>American influence</h2>

<p>The near-complete destruction of Rotterdam after the Nazi bombing raid of 14 May 1940, and its subsequent rebuilding means this city has a modern flavour. The randomness of its architecture was immediately evident upon stepping out of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rotterdam_Centraal_railway_station">railway station</a>. Its bold triangular metallic canopy pointed up into the clear royal blue sky, and drew my eye to the overbearing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Millennium_Tower_(Rotterdam)">Manhattan Hotel</a>, a skyscraper clearly influenced by the design of the Empire State Building.</p>

<p>Skyscrapers are a familiar sight in Rotterdam. This is especially true of the newly regenerated Kop van Zuid district, which has some similarities with London&#8217;s Docklands. Although much smaller, this district is already home to the work of architects like Renzo Piano, Sir Norman Foster and Rem Koolhaas.</p>

<figure class="tandem">
    <img src="/_assets/2015/06/rotterdam_kpn_tower.jpg" alt=""/>
    <img src="/_assets/2015/06/rotterdam_de_rotterdam.jpg" alt=""/><br/>
    <figcaption>
        <p>Details of KPN Tower and De Rotterdam buildings in the Kop van Zuid district</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Buildings here include <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maastoren">Maastoren</a>, the tallest building in the Benelux region, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/De_Rotterdam">De Rotterdam</a>, whose four substantial towers, each offset half way up, combine to form the most densely built part of the Netherlands. The area is joined to the city by the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Erasmusbrug">Erasmusbrug</a>, a landmark nicknamed &#8216;the Swan&#8217; due the design of its asymmetric white pylon.</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/_assets/2015/06/rotterdam_erasmusbrug.jpg" alt=""/>
    <figcaption>
        <p>Erasmusbrug or &#8216;The Swan&#8217;</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Other parts of the city are more human scaled, although even the Cool district, with its tree lined streets, are framed by the sight of tower blocks in the distance. The location of many restaurants and bars, it was here that I decided that this is a very easy city to live in  &#8211;  although the delicious coffee and a Chorizo and Cheese tosti from <a href="https://foursquare.com/v/hopper-coffee--bakery/4d302a752748b60c5f03d9a0">Hooper Coffee</a> may have swayed me!</p>

<h2>Waxing Arcs</h2>

<p>At the <a href="http://www.boijmans.nl/en/">Museum Boijmans Van Beuningen</a> the work of celebrated Dutch and international artists hang, but the most interesting piece is Richard Serra&#8217;s <em>Waxing Arcs</em>, two rusty steel arcs that stand in an otherwise empty gallery.</p>

<p>Their controversial history is told in <a href="http://www.boijmans.nl/en/7/calendar-exhibitions/calendaritem/1592/richard-serras-waxing-arcs">a multimedia presentation</a> that projects images onto the floor and onto the piece itself. The work Serra conceived as a reaction to the space it occupied was intended to direct viewers around the space in a specific way. When Wim Crouwel became director of the museum two years after it was installed, this space was enlarged and suddenly Serra&#8217;s work had the fortuitous effect of directing people into the museum shop. At one point, it even became part of the entrance foyer, much to the chagrin of its creator. This presentation tells the story of the space, and considers the way works of art can change over time, both as a result of the artist and the whims of those who commission them.</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/_assets/2015/06/rotterdam_boijmans.jpg" alt=""/>
    <figcaption>
        <p>Museum Boijmans Van Beuningen</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<h2>Euromast</h2>

<p>Boijmans is surrounded by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Museumpark">Museumpark</a>, an intriguing aspect of the city seeming intended to make the arts more accessible to residents. This isn&#8217;t too far from another park that lies within the shadow of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Euromast">Euromast</a>.</p>

<p>While not as tall or as beautiful as other tall towers, it is more frightening than most given an observation deck is open to the elements at a height of 100 meters. A further climb up three flights of step brings you to the entrance of the Euroscope, a rotating enclosed platform that lifts passengers close to the top of the 184 meter tall tower. I found the entire experience rather terrifying, so had nothing but admiration for those who were abseiling down the building.</p>

<h2>Cube Houses</h2>

<p>Another series of distinctive buildings can be found around Blaak railway station, the newest of which is the Markthal, a large arch-like structure enclosed with glass walls at each end and featuring ceiling art displaying enlarged fruits and vegetables. The strangest of Rotterdam&#8217;s buildings however must be the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cube_house">Cube Houses</a>, designed by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Piet_Blom">Piet Blom</a>.</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/_assets/2015/06/rotterdam_cube_houses.jpg" alt=""/>
    <figcaption>
        <p>Piet Blom&#8217;s Cube Houses</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Envisaged as an urban forest, this series of 40 cubes, each tilted at an angle of 45 degrees and perched upon hexagonal concrete trunks, allows residents to feel connected both to the street below, and the sky above. A show cube is open to the public, so I couldn&#8217;t resist peeking inside. As suspected, these homes are demonstrative of form over function; dangerously steep stairs lead up to a space divided into three floors, with small rooms constrained by steeply slopping ceilings.</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/_assets/2015/06/rotterdam_road.jpg" alt=""/>
    <figcaption>
        <p>Wide thoroughfares though the city reminded me a little of Brasilia, although here they are straddled by segregated cycle lanes and footpaths</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>As the Netherlands second largest city, and home to Europe&#8217;s largest port, Rotterdam has a lot to offer. It clearly has a self-assuredness and with a willingness to experiment but also have fun. Public art can be seen across the city, much of it intriguing, some of it just plain daft  &#8211;  I&#8217;m not sure most cities would have a 12 foot statue of Santa holding a butt plug in a main shopping district!</p>

<p>Modern, spacious, friendly, fun and daring, this could only be Rotterdam.</p>
]]>
            
            
        </content>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>William Kentridge - If We Ever Get to Heaven</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/2015/06/william_kentridge/"/>
        <id>tag:paulrobertlloyd.com,2015://2.440</id>
        <published>2015-06-21T13:54:51Z</published>
        <updated>2015-06-21T14:08:08Z</updated>
        <summary>The work of celebrated illustrator and artist William Kentridge is showcased at the EYE Film Institute in Amsterdam.</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Robert Lloyd</name>
            <uri>http://paulrobertlloyd.com/</uri>
        </author>
        <category term="exhibition" label="Exhibition" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="williamkentridge" label="William Kentridge" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/>
        <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/">
            <![CDATA[<img src="/_assets/2015/06/william_kentridge.jpg" alt="William Kentridge - If We Ever Get to Heaven"/>]]>
            
            <![CDATA[<p>Amsterdam is a strikingly beautiful city, every street a picture postcard. This beauty is somewhat undermined by the city&#8217;s famed seedy underbelly, which could be ignored were it not for the type of tourist it attracts.</p>

<p>With that in mind, I took the short ferry trip over to the quieter bank of the IJ, and visited the <a href="https://www.eyefilm.nl/en">EYE Film Institute</a>. While initially attracted by the building&#8217;s distinctive shape and sharp lines, it was a showcase of work by illustrator and animator <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_Kentridge">William Kentridge</a> that had me transfixed.</p>

<p>The work of Kentridge is often created as a response to the social injustices he has seen in his native south Africa, and politics is a theme that resonates throughout his work. The centrepiece of this particular exhibition is <cite>More Sweetly Play the Dance</cite>, a 45-meter-long illuminated frieze. This depicts a parade of silhouetted figures marching in a procession, some carrying personal affects, others holding up the faces of Chinese revolutionaries, miners and ancient Romans, and takes place against the sound of brass, accordions and African song.</p>

<div class="object youtube">
    <iframe src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/rkpaMYQdlSE?controls=0&amp;showinfo=0&amp;?rel=0&amp;?modestbranding=1" width="500" height="300" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>

<p>A second room contains eight screens for <cite>I Am Not Me, the Horse Is Not Mine</cite> (2008), an installation based on <cite>The Nose</cite>, a short story by the Russian writer Nikolai Gogol from 1836. However, it was <cite>Other Faces</cite> (2011), the tenth and most recent piece from his series <cite>Drawings for Projection</cite> (1989-2011) that I found truly exceptional. During this nine-minute long film, Kentridge films his own charcoal drawings, erasing and redrawing them  &#8211;  history constantly being overwritten  &#8211;  with each frame a work of art in its own right.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.eyefilm.nl/en/exhibitions/william-kentridge-if-we-ever-get-to-heaven-0"><cite>If We Ever Get to Heaven</cite></a> runs until 30 August.</p>
]]>
            
            
        </content>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>Two Years Hence</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/2015/06/two_years_hence/"/>
        <id>tag:paulrobertlloyd.com,2015://2.439</id>
        <published>2015-06-09T22:35:51Z</published>
        <updated>2015-06-09T22:48:04Z</updated>
        <summary>For the last few years I&#8217;ve employed a little life hack: signing up my future self to things I would ordinarily avoid.</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Robert Lloyd</name>
            <uri>http://paulrobertlloyd.com/</uri>
        </author>
        <category term="glasgow2014" label="Glasgow 2014" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="london2012" label="London 2012" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="thepastryboxproject" label="The Pastry Box Project" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="writing" label="Writing" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/>
        <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/">
            
            
            <![CDATA[<p>With a natural limit for how long I can spend around a group of people, I tend to operate a policy of minimal viable social interaction. This probably makes me an introvert, but I think of it more as my resting state. In the right circumstances, I can actually be quite outgoing, especially when in familiar environments among people I know. Put me on a stage, and I can really thrive.</p>

<p>However, I&#8217;m hesitant about signing up for public engagements, perhaps for fear of embarrassment or a bruised ego but also, frankly, anything for an easy life. Yet pushing beyond my comfort zone helps me grow as a person. And besides, the adrenaline that follows can give me the confidence I so often lack.</p>

<p>There&#8217;s an old Hindu saying: &#8216;In the first thirty years of your life, you make your habits; for the last thirty, your habits make you.&#8217; If I&#8217;m not careful, my tendency towards introversion could mean I let opportunities pass me by.</p>

<p>For the last few years I&#8217;ve employed a little life hack: signing up my future self to things I would ordinarily avoid. In 2010, I applied to be a Games Maker at London 2012. This was a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity, but one that would mean interacting with the public. It being some time away, I applied knowing I could defer those fears. Two years later, and there I was in the Olympic Park, high-fiving members of the public with my big pink foam finger and leading chants over a megaphone: &#8220;If you&#8217;re happy and you know it, clap your hands!&#8221;</p>

<p>I repeated the same trick in 2012 when I applied to be a volunteer at the Glasgow 2014 Commonwealth Games. I had a clearer idea of what was involved, but again was unsure about dealing with the public. Soon enough, I was directing people towards Hampden Park stadium, dressed in an unflattering poncho, singing in the rain and cheekily stealing people&#8217;s chips.</p>

<p>Clearly this little hack is working. So, what do I sign up for next?</p>

<p><em>This entry originally appeared on <a href="https://the-pastry-box-project.net/paul-lloyd/2015-may-12">The Pastry Box Project</a></em></p>
]]>
            
            
        </content>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>Apple: it&apos;s not you, it&apos;s me</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/2015/06/apple_keynotes/"/>
        <id>tag:paulrobertlloyd.com,2015://2.438</id>
        <published>2015-06-08T21:36:06Z</published>
        <updated>2015-06-09T00:10:23Z</updated>
        <summary>I tuned in for just a few seconds, but had to turn it off. That&#8217;s not enough time to make a reasoned judgement about the content of Apple&#8217;s latest keynote of course, but I just couldn&#8217;t continue watching.</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Robert Lloyd</name>
            <uri>http://paulrobertlloyd.com/</uri>
        </author>
        <category term="apple" label="Apple" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/>
        <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/">
            
            
            <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://twitter.com/paulrobertlloyd/status/607965028705267713">I tuned in for a few seconds, but had to turn it off</a>. That&#8217;s not enough time to make a reasoned judgement about the content of <a href="http://www.apple.com/live/2015-june-event/">Apple&#8217;s latest keynote</a> of course, but I just couldn&#8217;t continue watching.</p>

<p>This wasn&#8217;t always the case as Apple keynotes were once something I relished.</p>

<p>I distinctly remember one event that took place in 2005. I&#8217;m not sure why this particular keynote sticks in the memory (I think the main announcement was the inclusion of television episodes on iTunes). I suspect having recently upgraded to broadband, this was the first for which I could stream the video. But that evening, like many before it, was entirely consumed by a few announcements made in California.</p>

<p>Today I find myself not only uninterested in Apple&#8217;s keynotes, but actually at a point where I can&#8217;t even watch them in the background. They have always been over-the-top in terms of presentation, with adjectives like &#8220;amazing&#8221;, &#8220;incredible&#8221;, &#8220;magical&#8221;, &#8220;gorgeous&#8221; <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Nx7v815bYUw">flowing like water</a>. But now they feel different, and I&#8217;m not sure why.</p>

<p>Perhaps it&#8217;s my familiarity with the formula. A video featuring the opening of a new Apple Store with all the irritating whooping and hollering that must accompany it. A series of bar charts showing incredible product adoption. A few choice quotes from favoured journalists. Another video, maybe Jony Ive talking at great lengths about the redesign of an internal fan. Next up it&#8217;s Craig Federighi building his part, one dad joke at a time. Then one more thing (maybe). Finally, finish with a brief comment from Tim Cook about how &#8220;only Apple can do this&#8221; before concluding with Coldplay performing a few tracks from their latest album.</p>

<p>Perhaps it&#8217;s because their products are no longer objects I desire, instead they have become simply tools I use to get my job done. Tools which everyone around me use as well; glowing Apples as far as the eye can see.</p>

<p>Or perhaps  &#8211;  and this might be the most likely reason  &#8211;  participating in a marketing exercise carried out by the world&#8217;s most profitable corporation isn&#8217;t the same as following a plucky little computer company with less than 5% market share. Apple do many good things, and Tim Cook seems to possess a strong moral compass, but that hasn&#8217;t directed him towards fixing the company&#8217;s tax avoidance strategies. If he made Apple a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benefit_corporation">B-Corp</a>, I might believe more of the rhetoric.</p>

<p>Apple are just another technology company, trying to sell me stuff I don&#8217;t want (and only sometimes need). And I no longer see the fun in that.</p>
]]>
            
            
        </content>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>UpFront Conference</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/2015/05/upfront/"/>
        <id>tag:paulrobertlloyd.com,2015://2.437</id>
        <published>2015-05-30T18:11:30Z</published>
        <updated>2015-05-30T21:31:09Z</updated>
        <summary>Earlier this month I attended UpFront Conference, an event organised by Dan Donald and other members of Manchester&#8217;s digital community.</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Robert Lloyd</name>
            <uri>http://paulrobertlloyd.com/</uri>
        </author>
        <category term="conference" label="Conference" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="webdesign" label="Web Design" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="webdevelopment" label="Web Development" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/>
        <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/">
            
            
            <![CDATA[<p>Earlier this month I attended <em><a href="http://upfrontconf.com/">UpFront Conference</a></em>, an event organised by <a href="http://hereinthehive.com/">Dan Donald</a> and other members of Manchester&#8217;s digital community that featured a range of talks of interest to developers and designers alike. Currently in the midst of preparing a talk of my own (the reason for this delayed review), the conference provided plenty of food for thought.</p>

<p><a href="http://bradfrost.com/">Brad Frost</a> kicked off proceedings with an entertaining talk about an <a href="http://atomicdesign.bradfrost.com/">atomic approach</a> to responsive design. <a href="http://www.aliciability.com/">Alicia Sedlock</a> followed, with a rare overview of the different tools available for unit, integration and visual regression testing. Modular design and test-driven development are common in other fields of software engineering; that such presentations featured so prominently, hints at a growing professionalism within the field of front-end development.</p>

<p>The line-up also featured speakers who explored more creative aspects of coding. <a href="http://soledadpenades.com/">Soledad Penad�s</a> demonstrated a networked peer-to-peer game in which a group of friends could create music together on their phones without being connected to the internet. <a href="http://benjaminbenben.com/">Ben Foxall</a>&#8217;s talk saw the venue morph into an aviary, with attendees phones tweeting and chirping the noise of rooks and kingfishers. Both highlighted the innovation possible on the web, although curtailed to a degree by the dominance of iOS, a platform that supports a single rendering engine, with limited or no support for many of the cutting-edge APIs that were being used.</p>

<h2>Universal design</h2>

<p>OpenType is another feature missing from iOS, a point raised by <a href="http://clagnut.com/">Richard Rutter</a> during a typically passionate <a href="http://webtypography.net/talks/upfront2015">talk about web typography</a>. His presentation benefited from plentiful rehearsal and refinement, and the same was true of <a href="http://www.maban.co.uk/">Anna Debenham</a>&#8217;s. I&#8217;ve seen Anna&#8217;s <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/anna/what-we-can-learn-from-game-console-browsers-1">talk about console browsers</a> a few times now, but a new section about universal design really underlined her broader message. She cited OXO, who <a href="http://www.oxo.com/universaldesign.aspx">design products that are as usable by as many people as possible</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>When all users&#8217; needs are taken into consideration in the initial design process, the result is a product that can be used by the broadest spectrum of users. In the case of OXO, it means designing products for young and old, male and female, left- and right-handed and many with special needs.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Browsing the web on game consoles, televisions (and yes, even watches) with their myriad capabilities and constraints, is a fantastic proxy for the universal yet hostile medium we should be designing for. Given our predisposition to focus on the latest hardware announced by Apple or Samsung, we&#8217;d do well to remember this wider array of connected devices.</p>

<p>Performance emerged a number of times throughout the day, with a talk dedicated to the subject by <a href="http://www.deanhume.com">Dean Hume</a>. One of my favourite talks was by <a href="http://www.yperezcruz.com/">Yesenia Perez-Cruz</a>, who spoke eloquently about making design <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/yeseniaperezcruz/design-decisions-through-the-lens-of-a-performance-budget">decisions through the lens of performance</a>. She described a journey from that of &#8216;reckless designer&#8217; producing image-laden websites, to one advocating the benefits of performance to clients, and working with teams that take collective responsibility for the quality of the final product.</p>

<h2>Preaching to the converted?</h2>

<p>Performance may have replaced responsive layout as our community&#8217;s primary concern, and rightly so. This fact is further underlined by the introduction of Facebook&#8217;s Instant Articles product, <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/media/2015/may/13/bbc-news-guardian-facebook-instant-articles">marketed as a reaction to a mobile web that has become too slow</a>. That announcement hung in the air like a bad smell, and informed many of the conversations I had with people after the event.</p>

<p>It seems like we&#8217;ve been talking about the importance of web performance for years, and yet the average size of a web page continues to increase. We advocate greater collaboration between designers and developers sitting side-by-side. And yet, companies continue to outsource front-end development to teams based in countries like Ukraine or India. Progressive enhancement has proven to be an effective and efficient means of building reliable web services. Any yet, client-side <abbr title="Model-view-controller">MVC</abbr> frameworks have become the tool of choice for many developers.</p>

<p>Events like UpFront are fantastic, and the team in Manchester deserve credit for organising an accessible and affordable event that featured an amazing and diverse line-up. I was particularly impressed that Dan reminded attendees of their <a href="http://upfrontconf.com/code-of-conduct.html">code of conduct</a> during his opening remarks; small details like this really matter.</p>

<p>However, I left Manchester wondering if we need little less talk and little more action. It often feels like we&#8217;re trapped inside a bubble; we attend conferences, read blog posts and nod in agreement with each other. Meanwhile the wider industry carries on regardless. Only so much can be achieved by attending (or speaking at) such events, surrounding ourselves with people we agree with. Real change will only happen when we take these messages to our clients, and educate those who pay our wages.</p>
]]>
            
            
        </content>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>HTTPS + Compression Considered Harmful?</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/2015/05/https_compression/"/>
        <id>tag:paulrobertlloyd.com,2015://2.436</id>
        <published>2015-05-03T21:51:36Z</published>
        <updated>2015-05-03T22:31:08Z</updated>
        <summary>I recently learnt about a security exploit that can occur when pages served over HTTPS use HTTP compression. Secure or fast, pick one?</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Robert Lloyd</name>
            <uri>http://paulrobertlloyd.com/</uri>
        </author>
        <category term="https" label="HTTPS" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="webdevelopment" label="Web Development" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/>
        <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/">
            
            
            <![CDATA[<p>As I get closer to launching my redesigned website (this side of Christmas would be nice), I wanted to ensure pages were served over <abbr title="HTTP Secure">HTTPS</abbr>. This reflects a broader community effort to make the web more secure and trustworthy, a move <a href="http://w3ctag.github.io/web-https/">encouraged by the <abbr title="World Wide Web Consortium">W3C</abbr></a>.</p>

<p>Enabling <abbr>HTTPS</abbr> wasn&#8217;t too difficult, largely thanks to <a href="https://www.joshemerson.co.uk/blog/secure-your-site">Josh&#8217;s excellent how-to guide</a>. He recommends getting a free certificate from <a href="https://www.startssl.com/">StartSSL</a>, but as I have sub-domains for different staging and image resizing servers, I bought a <a href="https://www.namecheap.com/security/ssl-certificates/wildcard.aspx">wildcard certificate from NameCheap</a> instead. The launch of <a href="https://letsencrypt.org">Let&#8217;s Encrypt</a> later this year should hopefully make this exercise easier and better yet, free.</p>

<h2>An unexpected consequence of enabling <abbr>HTTPS</abbr></h2>

<p>With my certificates installed and <abbr>HTTPS</abbr> enabled, I visited my site and smiled broadly as I saw a little lock icon next to my domain. Ah, such simple pleasures.</p>

<p>One reason for enabling <abbr>HTTPS</abbr> was to examine its impact on performance, so I submitted my newly secured site to <a href="https://developers.google.com/speed/pagespeed/insights/">Google&#8217;s Page Insights</a> tool. Expecting a 100% score for speed as I had before, I instead got a value in the low 90% range. <a href="https://developers.google.com/speed/docs/insights/EnableCompression">Enabling compression</a> would reduce the response size of my static assets, I was told. But wait, I <em>had</em> enabled compression. Why was this setting not being respected?</p>

<p>I eventually realised this was a server related issue<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup>, yet my original line of enquiry had me believe compression was disabled because using both <abbr title="Secure Sockets Layer">SSL</abbr><sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2">2</a></sup> and <abbr>HTTP</abbr> compression could make a site vulnerable to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BREACH_(security_exploit)"><abbr title="Browser Reconnaissance and Exfiltration via Adaptive Compression of Hypertext">BREACH</abbr></a> attack. This was the first time I had heard about such an exploit, which I find surprising given that it can occur when authors follow two sets of best practice. More precisely, a site is vulnerable to this attack when pages:</p>

<ul>
<li>Are served from a server that uses <abbr title="Hypertext Transfer Protocol">HTTP</abbr>-level compression</li>
<li>Reflect user-input in <abbr>HTTP</abbr> response bodies</li>
<li>Reflect a secret (such as a <abbr>CSRF</abbr> token) in <abbr>HTTP</abbr> response bodies</li>
</ul>

<p>Any discussion about encryption usually leaves me confused and befuddled (the shear number of abbreviations doesn&#8217;t help), but the <abbr>BREACH</abbr> team suggest a number of ways to <a href="http://breachattack.com/#mitigations">mitigate against an attack</a>. Ordered by effectiveness, it&#8217;s worth noting that their first suggestion is to simply disable <abbr>HTTP</abbr> compression. Given the impact this can have on performance, that&#8217;s quite concerning.</p>

<p>My new website serves only static resources (pages are generated using <a href="http://jekyllrb.com">Jekyll</a> on my local machine), does not submit any form data (my contact form uses <a href="https://formspree.io">Formspree</a>, a third-party service), and does not transmit any sensitive data. Therefore I believe it&#8217;s safe for me to continue using compression. However, if you have a website that posts sensitive data (perhaps you have a secure admin area), you may wish to investigate this issue further.</p>

<p>In the meantime, perhaps there needs to be a discussion about which approaches will help us build websites that are both secure <em>and</em> fast.</p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes">
    <ol>
        <li id="fn:1">
            <p>I originally thought I wasn&#8217;t able to override this behaviour because requests to my custom-configured nginx instance are proxied via WebFaction&#8217;s <a href="http://docs.webfaction.com/user-guide/websites.html#creating-a-website">own front-end nginx process</a>. After considerable head scratching, I realised several conflicting nginx processes were running. Quitting these and starting a new single process fixed the issue. <a href="#fnref:1">&#8617;</a></p>
        </li>
        <li id="fn:2">
            <p>Compression has to be <a href="http://nginx.com/resources/admin-guide/compression-and-decompression/">enabled in nginx</a> regardless of protocol. <a href="#fnref:2">&#8617;</a></p>
        </li>
    </ol>
</div>
]]>
            
            
        </content>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>TTIP and the Near-stateless Global Giants</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/2015/04/ttip/"/>
        <id>tag:paulrobertlloyd.com,2015://2.435</id>
        <published>2015-04-20T00:18:55Z</published>
        <updated>2015-04-20T01:34:08Z</updated>
        <summary>The feedback loops and network effects permitted by the internet have allowed companies like Google, Facebook and Amazon to become near-monopolies within their chosen fields.</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Robert Lloyd</name>
            <uri>http://paulrobertlloyd.com/</uri>
        </author>
        <category term="europeanunion" label="European Union" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="google" label="Google" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="politics" label="Politics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="siliconvalley" label="Silicon Valley" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="ttip" label="TTIP" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/>
        <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/">
            
            
            <![CDATA[<p>Last week, the Guardian&#8217;s James Ball <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2015/apr/16/challenge-google-while-we-can-eu-anti-trust">wrote about the <abbr>EU</abbr>&#8217;s recently reopened anti-trust battle with Google</a>. Although relatively narrow (the investigation is looking at whether Google&#8217;s search results favour its own shopping service over rivals), Ball argues that should Google win, regulators will hesitate to investigate the activities of other internet behemoths.</p>

<h2>Network Effect</h2>

<p>Ball&#8217;s piece is short, so rather than quote the entirety of it here (I&#8217;m tempted), <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2015/apr/16/challenge-google-while-we-can-eu-anti-trust">I urge you to read it</a>. However, the essence of his article centres on the following:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>For all their promise of openness and equality, the technologies of the internet also promote the creation of giant companies.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Without going into the realms of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technological_determinism">technological determinism</a>, the feedback loops and network effects permitted by the internet have allowed companies like Google, Facebook and Amazon to become near-monopolies within their chosen fields. Fuelled by these factors, their growth continues to accelerate, unchecked.</p>

<p>This is something <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/paulrobertlloyd/fear-uncertainty-and-doubt">I&#8217;ve spoken about before</a>, so reading Ball&#8217;s article was largely an exercise in head nodding. However, the role of the <abbr>EU</abbr> as the last effective bastion of consumer protection is worth noting. Ball writes:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>&#8230;there are very few government bodies in the world with the scale to truly hold the largest internet giants to account  &#8211;  perhaps only the <abbr>US</abbr> and the <abbr>EU</abbr>. The companies can move their servers, their regional offices and their headquarters with relative ease. It&#8217;s only those places with enough customers to be irresistible that can try to enforce a rulebook.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>He later states:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Traditionally, <abbr>US</abbr> regulators have been relaxed about companies gaining large market share provided they don&#8217;t use their market power to get advantages in other sectors. European regulators have generally stepped in earlier, capping share.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The <abbr>EU</abbr> is often derided in Britain, but <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2014/dec/19/10-diktats-from-brussels-that-are-ruining-life-in-britain">many of its diktats</a> have made Europe a safer, fairer and more just place to live.</p>

<h2>TTIP</h2>

<p>Enter the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transatlantic_Trade_and_Investment_Partnership">Transatlantic Trade and Investment Partnership</a> or <abbr>TTIP</abbr>, the trade and investment deal currently being negotiated between the <abbr>EU</abbr> and <abbr>US</abbr>. Beyond reducing trade tariffs, this agreement is primarily focused on removing &#8216;non-tariff barriers to trade&#8217; by harmonising regulation between the two trading blocks.</p>

<p>This is where the relaxed nature of <abbr>US</abbr> regulation becomes a problem. For example, the <abbr>EU</abbr> has a precautionary principle that any new technology or product must be proven to cause no harm before entering the market, but the <abbr>US</abbr> has no such equivalent. Regulatory convergence would therefore impact working conditions, environmental protections, food safety and financial regulation, compliance falling to that of lowest common denominator.</p>

<p>This harmonisation would be result of a mechanism known as the &#8216;Investor-State Dispute Settlement&#8217; (<abbr>ISDS</abbr>). This gives corporations the power to sue governments for the potential reduction of profits resulting from a law being made. This clause is already present in similar trade agreements  &#8211;  you may have heard about <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6UsHHOCH4q8">Philip Morris&#8217; attempts to sue the Australian government</a> for introducing plain packaging on cigarettes.</p>

<p><abbr>ISDS</abbr> disputes take place in secret and bypass and override domestic judicial systems. Any attempts at nationalisation, regulation or consumer protection would soon feel the chilling effects.</p>

<h2>Combination</h2>

<p>The impact of <abbr>TTIP</abbr> has been largely ignored during this general election campaign (noticeably so by <abbr>UKIP</abbr>), receiving passing mention in what often sound like academic debates about privatisation of the <abbr>NHS</abbr>. The main parties (including Labour) are largely positive towards the agreement, believing it will boast trade and reduce unemployment, regardless of <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/260380/bis-13-1284-costs-and-benefits-of-an-eu-usa-investment-protection-treaty.pdf">studies that prove the opposite</a>.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s worrying to think how legislation like <abbr>TTIP</abbr>, designed to liberalise markets, would further empower those corporations born on the internet. As their interests extend to the devices embedded within every aspect of our lives (with the data flowing between them co-opted by the national security services), it&#8217;s hard not to see a future where we citizens become merely serfs, feeding the machine its daily diet of clicks and taps.</p>
]]>
            
            
        </content>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>Better Than It Was Before</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/2015/04/better_than_it_was_before/"/>
        <id>tag:paulrobertlloyd.com,2015://2.434</id>
        <published>2015-04-12T16:39:19Z</published>
        <updated>2015-04-12T17:02:08Z</updated>
        <summary>Finding parallels between redecorating my house and redesigning a website.</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Robert Lloyd</name>
            <uri>http://paulrobertlloyd.com/</uri>
        </author>
        <category term="thepastryboxproject" label="The Pastry Box Project" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="writing" label="Writing" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/>
        <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/">
            
            
            <![CDATA[<p>I moved in to my house at the end of 2013 and, for much of last year, lived in it as the previous owner had left it.</p>

<p>Dirty marks highlighted where pictures previously hung, paint peeled off walls where it was poorly applied, electrical sockets clung on to their oversized holes.</p>

<p>A long break over Christmas provided an opportunity to finally redecorate. This only served to force closer inspection; paint splashes on woodwork, windows featuring layers of paint that ought to be stripped back, uneven joins between walls and ceilings. Redecorating fixed some of these issues but also introduced further blemishes  &#8211;  more areas to enrage an occupant too often concerned with perfection.</p>

<p>Throughout this entire exercise, I would think &#8220;well, at least it&#8217;s better than it was before&#8221;, a means of bargaining with myself in an attempt to finish the task before the holiday was over.</p>

<p>Returning home after my first day back at work, I entered my newly decorated flat and was overcome with joy, all those little blemishes had faded away. Each room was no longer a to-do list, my house was now a home.</p>

<p>This got me thinking of the parallels between redecorating a house and redesigning a website. Whenever a project fails to turn out as expected, commiserating with colleagues often leads to someone uttering the immortal words: &#8220;well, at least it&#8217;s better than it was before&#8221;.</p>

<p>Too often I think about how I can make the world a better place: socially equal, ecologically minded. This only serves to frustrate when I realise changing the world requires large amounts of money, time, resources and influence.</p>

<p>I can only achieve so much on my own, but I can inspire, influence and lead by example. Leaving things in a better condition than I found them, seems like a good place to start.</p>

<p><em>This entry originally appeared on <a href="https://the-pastry-box-project.net/paul-lloyd/2015-march-12">The Pastry Box Project</a></em></p>
]]>
            
            
        </content>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>100 Days</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/2015/04/100_days/"/>
        <id>tag:paulrobertlloyd.com,2015://2.433</id>
        <published>2015-04-03T18:58:41Z</published>
        <updated>2015-04-03T20:00:14Z</updated>
        <summary>I&#8217;ve returned to 68 Middle Street just in time for the start of 100 days, a collaborative project where the aim is to complete a creative process every day for one hundred days.</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Robert Lloyd</name>
            <uri>http://paulrobertlloyd.com/</uri>
        </author>
        <category term="100days" label="100 days" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="clearleft" label="Clearleft" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="drawing" label="Drawing" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="freelance" label="Freelance" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/>
        <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/">
            <![CDATA[<img src="/_assets/2015/04/100_days.jpg" alt="100 Days"/>]]>
            
            <![CDATA[<p>Although Clearleft was first on the list of companies I&#8217;d like to freelance for, I was hesitant about having them be my first client, as it might throw into question <a href="/2013/10/moving_in_moving_on">why I left in the first place</a>. Thankfully doing so has actually validated my decision to spend <a href="/2015/01/changing_gears">14 months at the Guardian</a>; I&#8217;ve been surprised by just how often that experience has enabled me to contribute more meaningfully to our work with <a href="http://johnlewis.com">John Lewis</a>.</p>

<p>I also returned to 68 Middle Street in time for the start of <a href="http://clearleft100days.tumblr.com"><em>100 days</em></a>, a project in which several members of the team are aiming to complete and document a creative process (a &#8216;design operation&#8217;) every day for one hundred days. Based on <a href="http://designobserver.com/feature/five-years-of-100-days/24678">Michael Bierut&#8217;s original idea</a>, it is less about producing consistently great work, but rather an exercise in perseverance; as Woody Allen said &#8220;Eighty percent of success is showing up&#8221;. The project started on 23 March and runs until 1 July 2015.</p>

<p>For my design operation, I&#8217;ve chosen to create a single-line drawing each day, a simple constraint that should help me produce a coherent body of work yet also allow a degree of flexibility as I progress.</p>

<p>12 days in, and I&#8217;m still enjoying the challenge, mainly as I&#8217;ve yet to fully master it. Illustrations have ranged from minimalist to expressive; some are quite detailed, others look more like deranged scribbles! I used to draw quite regularly as a child, but as graphic design drew me ever closer to the computer screen, the habit receded. It&#8217;ll be interesting to see if this project reverses that trend.</p>
]]>
            
            
        </content>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>Link: The Billionaire&apos;s Typewriter</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://practicaltypography.com/billionaires-typewriter.html"/>
        <id>tag:paulrobertlloyd.com,2015://3.432</id>
        <published>2015-03-24T12:59:18Z</published>
        <updated>2017-01-02T19:35:14Z</updated>
        <summary>Matthew Butterick&#8217;s scrutiny of Medium reveals it to be &#8220;a form of human fracking&#8221;: In &#8220;Death to Typewriters,&#8221; Medium insists that the typewriter is its &#8220;sworn enemy.&#8221; In certain typographic details, maybe so. But as a device that imposes homogeneous&#8230;</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Robert Lloyd</name>
            <uri>http://paulrobertlloyd.com/</uri>
        </author>
        <category term="ethics" label="Ethics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="siliconvalley" label="Silicon Valley" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="webdesign" label="Web Design" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/>
        <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/">
            
            
            <![CDATA[<p>Matthew Butterick&#8217;s scrutiny of Medium reveals it to be &#8220;a form of human fracking&#8221;:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>In <a href="https://medium.com/designing-medium/death-to-typewriters-9b7712847639">&#8220;Death to Typewriters,&#8221;</a> Medium insists that the typewriter is its &#8220;sworn enemy.&#8221; In certain typographic details, maybe so. But as a device that imposes homogeneous design, Medium still has a lot in common with the typewriter.</p>

<p>In fact, its ethics are actually <em>worse</em> than the traditional typewriter. Why? Because Medium&#8217;s homogeneous design has nothing to do with limitations of the underlying technology (in this case, the web)&#8230; it&#8217;s a deliberate choice that lets Medium extract value from the talent and labor of others.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Convenience always has a cost.</p>
]]>
            
            <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/2015/03/the_billionaires_typewriter/" title="Permalink">#</a></p>]]>
        </content>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>Jake Archibald: Building SVGO&apos;s Missing GUI</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/2015/03/svgomg/"/>
        <id>tag:paulrobertlloyd.com,2015://2.431</id>
        <published>2015-03-23T13:26:25Z</published>
        <updated>2015-03-23T14:25:31Z</updated>
        <summary>SVGOMG is a wonderful example of how to build a web app in a responsible and accessible way. I asked its creator, Jake Archibald, a few questions about how he designed and developed this native-feeling SVG optimisation application.</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Robert Lloyd</name>
            <uri>http://paulrobertlloyd.com/</uri>
        </author>
        <category term="svg" label="SVG" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="webdevelopment" label="Web Development" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/>
        <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/">
            <![CDATA[<img src="/_assets/2015/03/svgomg.jpg" alt="Jake Archibald: Building SVGO's Missing GUI"/>]]>
            
            <![CDATA[<p>Having spent many hours simplifying, optimising and minifying <abbr>SVG</abbr>s, typically using a combination of tools and services, I was overjoyed to learn that <a href="http://jakearchibald.com">Jake Archibald</a> had <a href="http://sarasoueidan.com/blog/svgo-tools/">taken it upon himself</a> to build a web-based GUI atop <a href="https://github.com/svg/svgo">SVGO</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://jakearchibald.github.io/svgomg/">SVGOMG</a> is easy to use and surfaces the range of optimisation options offered by <abbr>SVGO</abbr>. But beyond the obvious utility, it stands out as an example of how to build a &#8216;web app&#8217; (<a href="https://adactio.com/journal/6246">whatever that means</a>) in a responsible and accessible way. I asked Jake a few questions about how he went about designing and developing this application.</p>

<h3>SVGOMG has a truly native app feel. What obstacles did you overcome (if any) to make it work so seamlessly on the web?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>It was easier than I expected, but I think I was expecting it to be impossible. I was surprised at how much I used <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/css-flexbox-1/">flexbox</a>, and how stable it is across modern browsers. Pretty much all of the layout is flexbox driven.</p>

<p>All the heavy lifting, such as <abbr>SVG</abbr> parsing and minification, happens in <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/workers/">web workers</a>, so the <abbr>UI</abbr> stays responsive. But the rule for runtime performance is still &#8220;if you paint, you lose&#8221;, so I had to spend time ensuring everything that moved had its own <abbr>GPU</abbr> layer and used simple transforms. There&#8217;s one downside to this, if you zoom the <abbr>SVG</abbr> preview in Chrome/Safari you start to see pixels. Still looking for a way to fix this that doesn&#8217;t kill performance.</p>

<p>I developed entirely in Chrome (disclaimer: I work at Google), then bug fixed in other browsers afterwards. Firefox pretty much worked straight away, in fact the issues were mostly down to stricter spec compliance. IE was okay, the bugs were mainly in newer and lesser used features such as <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/FileAPI/#url">blob <abbr>URL</abbr>s</a>. The biggest disappointment was Safari.</p>

<p>I was shocked how much hacking Safari needed to get basic features working. Smooth scrolling within an element still needs a custom property, which will simply stop working when combined with other properties like <abbr>CSS</abbr> animations. Every tap in iOS Safari comes with a 300ms delay. You can work around this with <a href="http://labs.ft.com/articles/ft-fastclick/">Fastclick</a>, but even the authors admit it&#8217;s a hack. I also found that features like <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/IndexedDB/">IndexedDB</a> disappear if the site is launched from a home screen icon. I hope Apple step up their game here!</p>
</blockquote>

<h3>One of the most pleasing features of the app is how it adapts to different screen sizes. Did you make any adaptions to your initial design/concept to achieve this?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>I&#8217;m terrible at design. I don&#8217;t know what I&#8217;m doing. I really don&#8217;t. [Google&#8217;s]  <a href="http://www.google.com/design/spec/material-design/introduction.html">Material Design</a> helped me a lot by telling me what to do. In the cases where Material Design didn&#8217;t have rules, I spent a long time sketching and throwing stuff out.</p>

<p>Unlike a lot of apps, the settings need to be visible alongside the output. It&#8217;s kinda tough to fit it all in on mobile, but I decided to split the output almost 50/50. The settings go at the bottom of the screen so you don&#8217;t cover the output with your hand while interacting.</p>
</blockquote>

<h3>What progressive enhancement techniques and approaches did you use to ensure the widest possible usage for the app?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>In terms of features, there are a couple of polyfills that are brought in dynamically for the browsers that need them. <abbr>IE</abbr> needs a <a href="https://github.com/jakearchibald/es6-promise">Promise polyfill</a>, Safari needs Fastclick.</p>

<p>I stuck to enhancing existing browser features rather than reinventing anything. The switches are all checkboxes underneath, styled using <code>&lt;label&gt;</code>s. I couldn&#8217;t style <code>&lt;input type="range"&gt;</code> how I wanted, so it&#8217;s just a series of divs, but there&#8217;s a real range input overlaid at <code>opacity: 0</code>, so you interact (with keyboard, mouse or touch) with the real thing, but the <code>&lt;div&gt;</code>s listen to events and provide the visual output.</p>

<p>I thought about making the site work without <abbr>JS</abbr> by doing the <abbr>SVG</abbr> work on the server, but this would be slow and a maintenance burden. I&#8217;m a strong believer in progressive enhancement, but also that each phase of the enhancement needs a user. Working without <abbr>JS</abbr> benefits older browsers, but as a site targeted at developers I figured I could safely leave older browsers behind.</p>
</blockquote>

<h3>You are a big proponent of web performance. What steps did you take to make the app feel so speedy?</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>Although I have no intention of making the site work without <abbr>JS</abbr>, I still render before <abbr>JS</abbr> is available. In fact, it gets to first render with only 5k of <abbr>HTML</abbr> with some inlined <abbr>CSS</abbr> and <abbr>SVG</abbr>, the main scripts and CSS are all loaded in the background. This means the site appears to load in 1.5s even on <abbr>3G</abbr> with an empty cache, and most of that is <abbr>DNS</abbr> and <abbr>SSL</abbr>.</p>

<p>The opening screen is really simple, so doing that in 5k wasn&#8217;t a challenge. It really bothers me that so many sites wait on <abbr>JS</abbr> for their first render, some even require their <abbr>JS</abbr> to make further requests before rendering. This pushes <abbr>3G</abbr> render time towards 10s  &#8211;  as a mobile user I know I wouldn&#8217;t put up with that.</p>

<p>The main <abbr>JS</abbr> is 15k, but doesn&#8217;t include the parts that parse and minify the <abbr>SVG</abbr>, that&#8217;s loaded as an extra phase in the background. It&#8217;s great because interactivity lands really quickly, and the user doesn&#8217;t notice the extra loading. If the user manages to select an <abbr>SVG</abbr> before that script is available, the loading of that script appears to be part of the processing time.</p>

<p>I also used <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/service-workers/">ServiceWorker</a> to make the whole thing work offline. Working offline is a pretty cool feature, but I&#8217;m mostly doing it for performance. Subsequent visits to SVGOMG render almost instantly, whatever connection the user has. Given the variations in mobile connectivity, that&#8217;s really valuable!</p>
</blockquote>
]]>
            
            
        </content>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>Briefly Berlin</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/2015/03/berlin/"/>
        <id>tag:paulrobertlloyd.com,2015://2.430</id>
        <published>2015-03-02T20:44:41Z</published>
        <updated>2015-03-02T23:59:41Z</updated>
        <summary>Before going freelance, I decided to take some time off during February. Part of this included spending a few days in Berlin.</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Robert Lloyd</name>
            <uri>http://paulrobertlloyd.com/</uri>
        </author>
        <category term="berlin" label="Berlin" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="europe" label="Europe" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="germany" label="Germany" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="travel" label="Travel" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/>
        <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/">
            <![CDATA[<img src="/_assets/2015/03/berlin.jpg" alt="Briefly Berlin"/>]]>
            
            <![CDATA[<p>Before <a href="/2015/01/changing_gears/">going freelance</a>, I decided to take some time off during February to visit my family in Brazil. Turns out, spending nearly three weeks with a large family crammed into a small flat, with two young  &#8211;  often screaming  &#8211;  children in searing hot weather is far from relaxing. By the end of my stay I was ill, wrung out and unsure if I wanted to spend a further three days in Berlin before returning home as originally planned.</p>

<p>Having landed at Sch�nefeld, acclimatised to the colder climate and checked in to my hotel, I spent the evening walking around the Mitte district, via <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gro�er_Tiergarten">Tiergarten</a> and the Brandenburg Gate. I was immediately struck by the peacefulness  &#8211;  appreciated after enduring the sound of a S�o Paulo suburb preparing for Carnival  &#8211;  and felt safe as I wandered round pointing my camera at points of interest. Germany couldn&#8217;t be any more different from Brazil, and Berlin proved to be the perfect way to unwind after the commotion of the previous week.</p>

<h2>First sight</h2>

<p>I always imagined the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brandenburg_Gate">Brandenburg Gate</a> as freestanding, separate from other buildings (as it was during the time of the Berlin Wall). Instead I found it surrounded on one side by a selection of bland and featureless offices that only serve to dilute the grandeur of the former toll booth through which Napoleon marched. I then headed towards <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Checkpoint_Charlie">Checkpoint Charlie</a>, fully aware of its slightly commercial appearance. Had I not read about this before, I may have been more astounded by the faux military personnel and illuminated signage.</p>

<p>Much of my first evening was spent trying to figure out how the metro system (S-Bahn and U-Bahn) worked. Routes are plentiful but share similar colours, and require knowing their final destination to ensure you board the right train. I was reminded of the adrenaline rush experienced by travelling in unfamiliar lands; a couple offering me their unused tickets served only to briefly confuse matters.</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/_assets/2015/03/berlin_ubahn.jpg" alt=""/>
    <figcaption>
        <p>A U-Bahn train arrives at Alexanderplatz station.</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The absence of entrance/exit barriers means the system relies heavily on trusting passengers, although needing to validate a ticket before travel seems designed to confuse tourists. Thankfully I worked this out before meeting one of the casually dressed yet intimidating ticket inspectors.</p>

<p>Other cities make much of their waterways, but the River Spree that runs though Berlin is easily missed. One area in which the river is made a feature is around <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Museum_Island">Museumsinsel</a>, a small island upon which a number of art galleries and museums sit. Upon my return home I discovered that I had in fact walked very close to the site of the former communist <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palace_of_the_Republic_(Berlin)">Palast der Republik</a>, a building I would loved to have seen before it was demolished.</p>

<h2>Olympiastadion</h2>

<p>A common aspect of my travels is visiting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Olympic_Stadium">former Olympic stadiums</a>, and this trip was no different. Germany has an unfortunate history relating to the Olympics; I had previously visited <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/paulrobertlloyd/4164185532/in/set-72157622824259243">the site of the 1972 massacre in Munich</a>, and here I was visiting the centrepiece of Hitler&#8217;s orchestrated event of 1936. Tourism can sometimes fell like a very crass activity.</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/_assets/2015/03/berlin_olympiastadion.jpg" alt=""/>
    <figcaption>
        <p>The imposing gates to Berlin&#8217;s Olympic Stadium.</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Olympic_Stadium_(Berlin)">This amphitheatre</a> modelled on the Roman Colosseum, was designed as a platform for Nazi propaganda, a means of drawing a line between Aryan superiority and Greek antiquity. The six columns surrounding the stadium represented the nationalistic ideology of the time in which Germans came from one of six clans: Bavarians, Prussians, Saxons, Frisians, Swabians and Franconians. On the east side of the stadium part of the arena is cut away. This is the Marathon Gate where the olympic cauldron is situated. This also provides a view towards the Maifeld parade ground and a bell tower which sits upon the Langemarckhalle, a memorial to young German soldiers who lost their lives during the First World War.</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/_assets/2015/03/berlin_olympiastadion-corridor.jpg" alt=""/>
    <figcaption>
        <p>Much of the stadium appears as it did during the 1936 Olympic Games.</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Phoney symbolism aside, the design of the seating bowl is actually quite smart, and much of this straight forward design remains untouched after the considerable refurbishment that took place prior to the 2006 World Cup. The outdoor swimming pool sat next to the stadium looks unloved in comparison, with both pools filled with rainwater.</p>

<h2>Berlin Wall</h2>

<p>The Olympiastadion is just one aspect of Berlin&#8217;s dark past. Many parts of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Berlin_Wall">Berlin Wall</a> remain, and opposite the <a href="http://www.berliner-mauer-gedenkstaette.de/en/">documentation and memorial centre</a>, one section has been restored to its original state. A further length of wall includes audio/visual presentations that describe the events that took place and show what the surrounding area previously looked like. Markings on the ground outline the location of buildings demolished to make way for the wall, while round metal plates indicate the points at which those attempting to cross the border were killed.</p>

<figure>
    <img src="/_assets/2015/03/berlin_wall.jpg" alt=""/>
    <figcaption>
        <p>A short section of restored Berlin Wall, complete with watch tower.</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Such shocking transparency brought home the dreadful and tragic situation Europe found itself during the last century. Hopefully having such a visible scar etched across Berlin will stop us from making the same mistakes again.</p>

<h2>Return visit</h2>

<p>Two full days wasn&#8217;t enough time to fully explore what this city has to offer. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reichstag_building">Reichstag building</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Berlin_Tempelhof_Airport">Templehof Airport</a> remain on my list, as do many of the museums and galleries. I took a real affection to this city, and in a strange way already miss being there. I&#8217;m sure it won&#8217;t be too long before I return.</p>
]]>
            
            
        </content>
    </entry>

    <entry>
        <title>Creative Direction</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/2015/02/creative_direction/"/>
        <id>tag:paulrobertlloyd.com,2015://2.429</id>
        <published>2015-02-12T15:57:41Z</published>
        <updated>2015-02-12T18:05:05Z</updated>
        <summary>For the last year I&#8217;ve been working at the Guardian under the leadership of a creative director. I&#8217;ve never worked with a creative director before  &#8211;  at least not in the traditional sense  &#8211;  and have found this to be a fascinating yet also frustrating experience; for the first time in my career I&#8217;ve not the been the arbiter of good taste.</summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Robert Lloyd</name>
            <uri>http://paulrobertlloyd.com/</uri>
        </author>
        <category term="design" label="Design" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="thepastryboxproject" label="The Pastry Box Project" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/><category term="writing" label="Writing" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag"/>
        <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="https://v2.paulrobertlloyd.com/">
            
            
            <![CDATA[<p>For the last year I&#8217;ve been working at the Guardian under the leadership of a creative director.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve never worked with a creative director before  &#8211;  at least not in the traditional sense  &#8211;  and have found this to be a fascinating yet also frustrating experience; for the first time in my career I&#8217;ve not the been the arbiter of good taste.</p>

<p>This situation might have been different if our creative instincts were aligned, but that has rarely been the case. When reviewing a design, sometimes I would be asked to position an element uncomfortably close to the edge of a container, or use heavier or larger type. And yet weeks later, when faced with a design that was the accumulation of decisions I hadn&#8217;t agreed with, I&#8217;d find myself content with the result, my eye no longer drawn to what I previously found unsightly.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve sometimes felt the same when looking at other people&#8217;s work. On seeing the first screenshots of iOS7, I recoiled at its flatness, the plainness of its typography, and those icons! But today I use my iPhone without taking much notice of this revised aesthetic. Was I too quick to judge, or have I simply grown used to those changes?</p>

<p>Of course, what constitutes good design is entirely subjective. Who is to say my judgements are better than those of another designer? Regardless of the decisions made internally, users of the product will no doubt have their own thoughts, too.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve come to believe that good design is ultimately about a consistency of execution, but great design requires something else: bravery. A willingness to make decisions that push beyond the boundaries of contemporary taste. Thinking of breakthrough products  &#8211;  the original iMac with it&#8217;s bulbous Bondi-blue case, the Ford Sierra&#8217;s aerodynamic styling, the minimalistic interface of Windows Phone 7  &#8211;  each was the result of decisions taken against the grain. Thinking back to those design reviews, perhaps I was witness to acts of similar importance, a participant in the continual refinement of prevailing fashion.</p>

<p>My year at the Guardian has taught me many things, but foremost is having the confidence to make braver choices. This year, should I find myself awkwardly positioning elements within a composition, I will try living with that decision for a few days rather than a few seconds.</p>

<p><em>This entry originally appeared on <a href="https://the-pastry-box-project.net/paul-lloyd/2015-january-12">The Pastry Box Project</a></em></p>
]]>
            
            
        </content>
    </entry>

</feed>